EDWARD NICOLASH

edwardnicolash@gmail.com | 085794194129 |www.linkedin.com/in/edward-nicolash/ | Jalan Turangga Timur II No. 42 Bandung 40264

ABOUT

After graduating from Institut Teknologi Bandung, I have over three years of experience in the financial sector, including two years in lending and one year in banking. Through these roles, I've learned that technology is impacting customer satisfaction. I've also observed a gap in certain technologies that weren't aligned with client needs. I'm eager to deepen my expertise as a Core Analyst in the financial industry, applying my background to bridge this gap and drive impactful contributions to the field.

EDUCATION

Institut Teknologi Bandung

Aug 2016 - Apr 2021

Bachelor Degree in Geophysical Engineering, GPA 3.20 / 4.00

- Dean's list on the 3rd Semester GPA 3.51 out of 4.00.
- Dean's list on the 5th Semester GPA 3.53 out of 4.00.
- Dean's list on the 8th Semester GPA 3.83 out of 4.00.

WORK EXPERIENCE

KEB Hana Bank – Jakarta Nov 2023 – Now

IT Digital Backend - Line Bank

- Develop API specifications and backend systems for Consumer Banking (Line Bank).
- Develop front-end and back-end web application for Channel Support with Yii2 PHP technology.
- Assisted business analysts in defining the scope of the Business Requirements Document (BRD) for the Channel Support web application.
- Collaborated with the operations team to identify and resolve backend bugs in the Line Bank mobile banking application.
- Contributed to mitigating security vulnerabilities identified through penetration test results for Line Bank.

Xsis Mitra Utama – Jakarta Nov 2021 – Nov 2023

Fullstack Technical Consultant - Mandiri Utama Finance

- Collaborate with Business Analysts to fullfill technology gaps in Business Requirements Documents (BRD).
- Analyze BRD (Business Requirement Definition) related to business and technical processes according to user requirements about Account Acquisition Management System.
- Managed vendor, by providing business insights to facilitate the integration of in-house and third-party web
 applications.
- Perform application testing to make sure development process fulfill BRD Requirements.

- Create task list of software development process according BRD using Microsoft Project.
- Perform application testing to make sure development process fulfill BRD Requirements.
- Support issues for testing the QC (Quality Control) environment and UAT (User Acceptence Test) environment.
- Coordinate with all related teams and give the best optional solutions so that the project development process until go-live production can running well.
- Analyze BRD (Business Requirement Definition) related to business and technical processes according to user requirements about Account Acquisition Management System.
- Handling and manage on vendor by giving knowledge business so the in house web application can integrate with web application their build
- Create task list of software development process according BRD using Microsoft Project.
 - Perform application testing to make sure development process fulfill BRD Requirements.
- Support issues for testing the QC (Quality Control) environment and UAT (User Acceptence Test) environment.
- Coordinate with all related teams and give the best optional solutions so that the project development process until go-live production can running well.
- Develop a full-stack (Frontend PHP CI, Backend Java Spring, Devops Openshift Jenkins and Database PL/SQL Query) web-based applications according to BRD within thight deadline.

Institut Teknologi Bandung - Karawang

Mar 2020

Research Assistant

- Coordinated with the manager in planning cost, workload, and job description
- Negotiated with local community to get access to work in there.
- Determined survey area acquisition to measure seismic passive data.
- Made a preliminary report from the survey area.

CERTIFICATION

Product Management (Binar Academy)

May 2022 - Jun 2022

- Learn how to conclude user needs and trend appropriate with company from BCG Matrix.
- Made user persona to understand the characteristics, motivations and goal of target users.
- Identify end-to-end user experience by mapping out key touch-point, define user pain points and design opportunities for improvement from Customer Journey Maps.
- Gained a foundation understanding of creating business requirement definitions.

Certified Application Security Engineer JAVA (EC Council) Jun 2022

May 2022 -

- Learn foundation skills about vulnerabilities that can arise in Java applications.
- Learn using scenario to identify potential security treats by modelling possible attack vector and vulnerabilities.

Web Development (Udemy Course)

May 2021 - Jun 2021

• Learn basic HTML, CSS3, Javascript, Node JS, and React JS by creating project.

ORGANIZATIONAL EXPERIENCE

Himpunan Mahasiswa Teknik Geofisika – Bandung

Feb 2019 - Jan 2020

Head of Human Resources Management

- Manage and led self development member by organize suitable job with skill and character.
- Create a conducive environment to work by create appreciating event to improve the performance and embrace member.
- Made member half years evaluations to improve the performance and manage durability.
- Collect data on member activities and achievements that have been obtained.

International Undergraduate Geophysics Competition

Sep 2018 - Nov 2018

Staff

- Coordinated with the event manager to prepare the necessary products for holding the main eventual.
- Negotiated with seller to get high quality products with best prices.

SKILLS AND CHARACTERISTICS

Characteristics
Fast learner
Adaptability
Open minded
High Achiever
Responsible
Target oriented
-